MainActivity is launched when you start the app. At the bottom of MainActivity,
we have PlaceholderFragment. PlaceholderFragment was generated by
the template we used when creating our project.
A fragment is a modular container within your activity. In later lessons,
we'll look at how to use multiple fragments in a single activity. And
we'll actually explain why, we're using them at all. But for now,
our activity contains just this one fragment. So here in PlaceholderFragment,
is where we reference our UI layout resource, called fragment main.
This XML file lives in the Resource's RES directory of our Project Folder. You
can see other kinds of resources here besides layouts, such as design assets or
drawables, or strings. When our activity runs, it creates this placeholder
fragment which then inflates the XML layout resource, converting everything in
the XML file to a hierarchy of view objects in memory. By holding CTRL or
CMD, depending on your operating system, and clicking on this reference to
fragment main. Android studio will drop us right into the visual layout editor.
Once we're inside a layout XML file, we can switch between the design tab,
where we can drag and drop new UI elements and modify the layout visually. And
the Text tab, where we can see and edit the XML that defined the layout and
UI elements. All of the views we'll talk about here ultimately extend the view
base class. The template we used gives us a relative layout, with some padding
around the edges. We'll get into layout features like padding and margins,
later. Inside our relative layout, is a single TextView that says, hello world.
EditText, is a text entry field that is an editable version of text view.
It has many options, such as whether it supports single or multi line.
There are several styled versions of editText, in the text field section of
android studio. Such as Name, E-mail, Phone, or
Postal Address. Each one sets the soft keyboard into an appropriate entry mode.
ImageView displays the image defined in its source attribute.
It has some really useful features. Like zooming and copying if the source file
is to large or has a different aspect ratio than the image view itself.
A list view is a special kind of view that contains one or
more view that are replicated to display sets of data. In this
case the single textView is used to display the weather information replicated
throughout the list. We'll get into much more detail about list view later on.